Previously on
"Gotham Knights"...
They think I killed my dad
because I wanted his money?
Cullen: We didn't kill your
dad any more than you did.
We're gonna clear our names.
We're a lot of things
but we're not cops.
Cullen: But whoever is
behind it is gonna make sure
we have a little accident.
[Ford and Carrie grunting]
Who the hell are you?
I'm Robin.
So, you knew my dad was Batman?
Mutant Gang threw
him off the roof
of my apartment.
I dragged him to safety.
Not a bad way to meet your hero.
Turner, he didn't want you
to follow down that path.
I swiped this from
Ford during our escape.
Duela: It's the symbol
of the Court of Owls.
They're the ones who
really run this city.
Have you forgotten
your debt of gratitude?
Just keep me in office so
I can continue to repay it.
We need to find out everything
we can about who's after us.
We got Bruce's journals.
Records of all of his cases.
Carrie: Come on. Let's go.
Stephanie: Anything interesting?
Turner: They ripped
out his final entry.
Whoever it was doesn't want
us to know what he wrote.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
Man: Watch it now.
[Engine starts]
[Van drives away]
You lost, little girl?
Yeah, I'm looking
for my Batarang.
Have you seen it?
Oh. There it is.
[Grunts]
[Batarang clatters]
[Both grunting]
Nice try.
Ha ha.
[Grunting]
Aha. Ha.
[Electricity
sizzling] [Groaning]
[Siren]
[Door closes]
[Indistinct voice on radio]
Carrie: Ahh.
Turner: You OK?
Carrie: I'm great.
Harper: Then I assume there's
someone somewhere
who's not great.
Yep. Guy about the
size of a refrigerator.
Bit of a temper. Goes by
the name Vernon Wagner.
Wait, you went up against the
leader of the Mutant Gang?
More like he went up
against me. And lost.
I've been tracking
them for weeks.
Got to say, worth it.
Cullen: So... so are they
called the Mutant Gang
'cause they're
actually, like, mutated
or just 'cause it sounds scary?
I'm thinking they're
a little less scary
without their leader.
Cullen: Oh. Turner: Nice work.
Thank you very much.
This one was kind of
personal, actually.
Probably should have
thanked the Mutant Leader.
He's the reason I met your dad.
And became his sidekick.
Yeah, you mentioned that.
So did my dad.
He wrote about it
in his journals.
So, how does that happen?
Is there, like, a
application process?
Batman took out an ad
in the "Gotham Gazette"?
Like "Mini-Bat wanted"?
The Mutant Gang threw
him off a building
in my neighborhood
and I pulled him to safety.
Oh, you saved Gotham's
savior. That's cute.
I was actually just
returning the favor.
He'd been protecting my neighborhood
since before I was born.
I thought I owed it
to Batman to help him
help the people who needed it.
Well, I look forward
to reading all about it
in this little, uh...
OK. Fine. Maybe later.
Anything in there that can help
us hunt down the Court of Owls?
A lot of conspiracy theories.
It's not exactly a how-to on
catching my dad's killers.
Nothing concrete. I
can't help thinking
the most important
pages were the ones
that were ripped out.
Well, um, I have an AP
Bio exam to cram for.
It's gonna do to me what
the Mutant Leader couldn't.
Does it say in here
why daddy didn't
pick you to be his sidekick?
I mean, Bat-points
for him not just doing
the whole nepotism
thing, and clearly,
Little Bird is qualified,
but I mean, come on,
It's gotta sting,
like, a tiny, bitty bit
that he just handed
his whole legacy to
some random stranger, right?
I'm sure he had his reasons.
OK.
News anchor: After the
Mutant Gang's reign of terror
following the death of Batman,
Gotham can sleep a
bit easier tonight
now that Vernon Wagner,
also known by his
nom de crime "The
Mutant Leader,"
is safely and, given
his sheer size,
snugly behind bars.
Celebrating this
victory was Mayor Hill.
Mayor Hill: On my order,
the brave men of the GCPD
have captured the
degenerate leader
of the Mutant Gang,
and starting today,
we're deploying 100 more
officers to hunt down
the rest of the Mutants.
And I can think of no
better way to celebrate
the taking back of our city than
at the Founders Gala tomorrow,
knowing that we made the
streets of Gotham safer today.
Man: Mr. Mayor! Mr. Mayor!
[Reporters shouting at once]
Man: Is that really gonna work?
Does it make the
streets of Gotham safer
when you pressure,
one of my ADAs into
dropping charges
against Brody March?
Kid clearly learned his lesson.
Came down to the
GCPD to confess.
Nobody got hurt and
no money was stolen.
Right, because it was donated
to your campaign coffers.
How big a contribution did Lincoln
March make to your re-election fund?
Why? You trying to figure
out how much you gotta
raise to beat me by November?
Or are you still too
scared to get in the race?
I'll see you at the gala.
[School bell rings]
"GCPD Captures
Mutant Gang Leader."
The press always gets it wrong.
We have AP English
together, right?
I'm Stephanie, you're Carrie,
and we have a lot more
in common than that.
Another case of a
man taking credit
for a woman's work.
I don't know what you mean.
Turner filled me in on
your extracurriculars.
Can't be easy, picking
up the Bat-mantle.
That why you're catching
extra Zs in the stacks?
I don't care if the
cops took credit.
I just wish Batman was here
to see me take him down.
You know, I knew Bruce a little.
He'd be proud of you.
Brody: Hey, Steph.
Um...
Carrie.
Well. I don't know
what's more surprising...
To see you actually
in the library
or to see you not behind bars.
Thanks again for
that, by the way.
Got 3 months community service.
Of course your dad got you off.
Pays to be a March. As
long as a March pays.
My parents are punishing
me in other ways. Trust me.
Anyway, the reason
I'm here in the...
What'd you call this
place? The... library?
Ha. Is because I
wanted to ask you
if you wanted to come to
the Founders Gala with me.
I know you hate those parties.
I hate those parties,
but come with me.
We can hate the party together.
Your dad legit just
got you out of jail.
Is he gonna let you
out of the house?
I told you my parents
were punishing me.
This is the punishment.
You in?
Turner: You said yes?
What was I supposed to say?
Brody lied to the police
about hacking the banks.
For me. I kind of owe him.
Duela: Yeah, I'm with
Brownie on this one.
I mean, you got her into
trouble, he got her out, so,
think that earns her a
ticket to the Brodeo.
Please stay off my side.
And I highly doubt
that me splitting
a cheese platter with Brody
is your most pressing concern.
OK. Where are you
on your clue trail?
At a dead end. But
check this out.
My dad wrote about his
theory that the Court of Owls
were hunting the Wayne
family for over 100 years.
Starting with his
great-great-grandfather Alan Wayne.
But all the accounts
of the time say that
he drowned in a sewer
when he accidentally
fell into a manhole.
Newspapers attributed
it to dementia but
here's where it
gets interesting.
Witnesses at the time said that
he was last heard screaming,
"The owls are in my house."
That can't be a coincidence.
Turner: Yeah.
Stephanie: So, what now?
Well, I know what the World's
Greatest Detective would do.
Can't solve the last murder,
go back to the first.
If the Court did
kill Alan Wayne,
maybe looking
through his cold case
will help us prove
they killed my dad.
Figure out how they
did it, maybe see if
we can find out
who was involved.
It's a long shot.
All cold cases are long shots.
But if you could get your hands
on the original case
file, maybe we could
find something the
police missed back then.
Yeah, if the original case file
wasn't collecting cobwebs
in the GCPD basement.
Stephanie: Right. Turner:
Can't exactly just
go and check it out.
No, but we could steal it.
Turner: How?
Cullen: Why don't ya
leave that to the
thieves to figure out?
Woman on TV: In a
stunning development,
the Mutant Gang has now
claimed responsibility for
last night's downing
of a GCPD airship
that crashed into Ace Chemicals,
causing widespread fires
that at this moment
have not been contained.
If not for the brave efforts
of Gotham's firefighters,
toxic fumes would
have surely been
unleashed upon the city.
The motive behind this
senseless act of terror
became clear when
the Mutant Gang
threatened a wave of
retaliatory violence
against those responsible for
the arrest of their leader.
Wagner and his Mutants are
also suspected of being
the masterminds behind the...
You take down the Mutants,
the GCPD takes the credit,
and then the Mutants take
it out on everybody but you.
I'm not sure if Batman would
be proud of you, but I sure am.
Turner: Wait. I'm
going with you.
This is my mess and
I'm gonna clean it up
before anyone else gets hurt.
You don't have to do it alone.
You were my dad's
backup. Let me be yours.
I appreciate the
offer. I really do.
But you have enough to do
trying to clear your names.
Not until we can jailbreak that
Alan Wayne file out of the GCPD.
Until then, I'm
out of breadcrumbs.
You know we made a pretty
good team against the Talon.
Maybe we treat the Mutant Gang
to a bit of that teamwork.
Look, the Talon is
a different story.
It's one thing to get
pulled into danger.
It's another to
go looking for it.
You're a wanted fugitive,
Turner. It's too big of a risk.
Is this about me getting
caught or me getting hurt?
It's about your
dad not wanting you
to follow down the same path.
You can't just walk into
the GCPD and take evidence.
You can if you're in a
cop uniform holding these.
Evidence transfer requests.
Some of my best work.
Just a couple of hours in
the Gotham Academy Art Lab.
Duela: Let me see.
Oh. Looks like the
real deal to me.
Harper: Your mug shot is
plastered all over the city.
How are you not
gonna be recognized?
I could help with that.
Look, they only know
me as a scared kid.
They're not expecting
a rookie cop.
Yeah. Exactly.
Which you aren't.
This is too dangerous.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
And you know what?
He can handle it.
The Talon would have
turned me into a patty melt
if he hadn't pulled
me out of that car.
And, aah, your problem
is that you are
so busy trying to
protect your brother
that you haven't noticed
that he doesn't need it.
So, maybe it's time
for you to recognize
that he's a total badass.
Toodles.
Thanks for sticking up for me.
It's nice to have
someone believe in me
even if it is you.
Oh, yeah, I just
said that because
there's something I
need you to do for me.
KiNG MALA: ♪ I don't
need your roses, I like ♪
♪ Men on their knees ♪
♪ Praying up to their god,
seein' visions of me ♪
♪ I'm a cult leader, mind
reader, heart eater ♪
♪ Fear feeder, say I'm
your favorite preacher ♪
♪ If I wasn't a narcissist,
I wouldn't like me either ♪
Woman: Mr. March, can we
get a picture over here?
KiNG MALA: ♪ I'm
a cult leader... ♪
Mr. and Mrs. March.
Please, call me Rebecca.
It's nice to finally meet you.
Rebecca: It's a shame we
won't be seeing your parents.
Your mom's been MIA from
the club for weeks now.
Yeah, Dad's taping
"Quiz Bowl" tonight.
Mom's been spending more time
at the studio to support him.
Rebecca: Of course. Well,
they must be so proud.
Brody told us you're on
the fast track for MIT,
following in your
dad's footsteps.
Same as Brody now
going to State.
Heard you were quite the
fencer in your day, Mr. March.
Won State 4 years running.
Shall we?
No pressure.
Lincoln: You'll do
fine. I'm certain.
Though I doubt we can
count on your next opponent
also being arrested for
murdering his own father.
Hey. How you doing?
KiNG MALA: ♪
Leader, leader, no ♪
♪ Leader, leader, leader, no ♪
[Tool whirring, snapping]
[Chirp]
[Gun clicks]
[Laughs]
Hi there.
[Whack] [Thud]
[Whispering] Turner,
what are you doing here?
Waiting on a "thank you" for
stopping him from shooting you?
One, I had him.
Two, now I can't
question him to find out
what they were planning next.
So, thank you.
How'd you even find this place?
The rocket that took
down that airship
came from the north, so,
from the point of impact,
it's a straight
line to this area.
There are, like, 50
warehouses in this area.
How did you narrow
it down to this one?
When I was little, my dad
and I used to play a game.
He called it "Sore Thumb."
Wherever we were...
Dinners, parties...
He would have me pick out
the thing that didn't belong.
I always thought
it was just a game
to entertain a bored kid,
but turns out...
He was teaching you
situational awareness.
Yup. So, when I saw
that this warehouse
was the only one
without security lights
and the gates were
padlocked from the inside,
I suspected somebody was
trying to hide something.
Looks like you put those
skills to good use.
I just can't figure out why
he would teach them to me
if he didn't want
me to use them.
I'm sure he had a reason.
Turner: These are
from Ace Chemicals.
So, it wasn't a
terrorist attack.
Crashing that airship into Ace
Chemicals was to cover the fact
that the Mutants were
robbing the place.
What are they planning to do
with a bunch of chemicals?
They're empty.
Whatever they were planning,
they already did it.
[Classical music playing]
[Indistinct chatter]
Good to see you, Martin.
Miss Brown.
How are you this evening?
Ah. Should I get my lawyer
down here before I answer that?
Lincoln: Harvey Dent.
Gotham's white
knight... in black tie.
Lincoln. Good to see you.
Have you met my wife Rebecca?
No, I don't believe I
have. Pleasure to meet you.
So, if you're here
glad-handing the donor class,
I assume the rumors are true
and you are running for mayor.
Right now, my focus is on
the current job I
was elected to do.
Is that right? All right.
Well, if you ever hope to be
a politician in this town,
better learn how to
lie better than that.
I have to disagree
with my husband.
I think you lie quite well.
I almost believed you when
you told him we'd never met.
[Helicopter flying]
[Elevator bell dings]
[Indistinct chatter]
Desk sergeant: Sign 'em out,
you gotta sign 'em back in.
It's called chain of custody.
Yeah.
Ahem.
How you doing?
Desk sergeant: What do you want? Cullen:
Yeah, I'm from Somerset Precinct.
I just got a case
file transfer request.
Does this look like the
Records Room to you?
Uh, uh...
Down the hall, third
door on the left.
Look for a sign
that says "Records."
Hey.
Do they not teach you
anything over there
at Somerset, rook?
Coffee. You come into another
man's shop asking for stuff,
a little juice of the
bean goes a long way.
Right. I'll... I'll remember
that, sir. Thank you.
Yeah. I'll remember you.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Door closes]
Uh, what's all this?
We were kind of hoping
you could tell us.
We found these chemicals
and some kind of blueprints
trashed at a Mutant
Gang stash house.
Any idea what they're up to?
Well, you've got nitrobromide
and uridium oxidate.
Not much you can
make out of those.
They're both solubles. They
wouldn't even cause a reaction
unless they were put under
pressure and aerosolized.
Damn. It looks
like they're making
some kind of poison gas bomb.
To gas the city?
No. If you release
it outdoors,
it'll dissipate too quickly.
For it to work, it needs
to stay concentrated,
like in an enclosed area.
Turner: The GCPD. Carrie: No.
Now that the cops
have Vernon in a cage,
I don't think the
Mutant Gang would risk
killing their leader.
Duela: I know what
my daddy would do.
He would make a statement.
All right. What
does poison gas do?
Uh, it kills people?
Well, yes, but how?
Carrie: It chokes you to
death. Duela: Ding ding ding!
Yes. And who better
to choke with it
than the people who've
had Gotham by the throat
since the very beginning?
The ones who are, as we speak,
congratulating themselves
between bites of
little, overpriced fish eggs.
The Founders Gala.
Yes! You are on fire
today, Little Bird.
I mean, come on. All those
well-heeled hypocrites,
just gasping for rarefied air.
The mayor. The
district attorney.
Stephanie.
[Classical music playing]
[Indistinct chatter]
Two virgin mojitos.
Really? 'Cause this one
tastes pretty slutty to me.
Yeah, I tipped the bartender
a 20 to pretend I'm 21.
You know, given our recent
brushes with the law,
I'm not sure adding
underage drinking
to our rap sheets
is a good idea.
You're about to have
dinner with my parents.
Trust me, you are
going to need it.
[Glasses clink]
Your mom seems nice.
[Chuckles]
And my dad?
Your mom seems nice.
Huh. Yeah. She is.
It's not always easy being
married to Lincoln March,
even though she makes
it seem that way.
Starting to get the sense
it's not easy being his son.
[Cell phone buzzing]
I have to get this. Sorry.
Yeah.
Yes, the party is awful,
the lava cake is garbage,
my feet are killing me, and
I'm having a terrible time.
Turner: Steph, listen. You
have to get out of there.
What? Why?
The Mutant Gang's about to do
something terrible.
[Indistinct voice
on police radio]
[Gunfire]
Officer: Who was that?
Officer 2: Shots fired.
[Gunfire, glass breaking]
[Indistinct voice
on police radio]
Man: Grenade!
[People screaming]
[Crowd screaming]
No need to panic.
We're just here to provide
the evening's entertainment.
Do you all like games?
Because I have one that
I think you'll love.
It's a very simple game.
It's called...
"What Does This Button Do?"
Male reporter: It's a chaotic
scene here at City Hall
as the Founders Gala
has been taken hostage
by the Mutant Gang, who have
barricaded themselves inside,
threatening to detonate
a chemical explosive
if the GCPD does not
release their leader,
Vernon Wagner, by
10 p.m. tonight.
In these dark times,
I'm sure I'm not alone
in feeling that Gotham
could use a Batman.
Woman on TV: Isn't that the
truth? In other news, Gotham...
So, you guys are... going in?
We were kind of hoping
you would join us.
Uh, why the hell
would I do that?
You know how to disable a bomb.
Yeah. Step One:
call the bomb squad.
Carrie: They don't have the
instruction manual. We do.
Besides, if they go in
and kick the door down,
then the Mutants will
just set off the bomb.
Sorry, how is what you're
planning any different?
Well, you don't have to
go through the front door.
Decommissioned subway tunnels
will take you right under it.
Then you could pop
up into City Hall
like a stripper
popping out of a cake.
But you would need someone to
open the door from the inside.
If I could arrange that,
would you show us the way?
Why would I risk my life
to save a bunch of people
who don't give a damn about me?
Same reason we saved
you from the Talon.
You do realize it's impossible
to guilt me into
anything, right?
Fine. You'll get to
punch a bunch of Mutants.
Oh! Should've led with that.
I'll get my purse.
P.A.: All officers, report
to the briefing room.
You.
Briefing. Now.
I really gotta get these records
down to Somerset, though.
All hands on deck, rook.
Hostage situation at City Hall.
Man: Briefing room. Now.
Man: Take a seat.
All right now. All
right, everybody.
Listen up. Settle down.
We got a hostage situation.
[Helicopter flying]
[Bell rings] [Banging]
[Banging]
Here you thought you wouldn't
make this year's Gala.
Not exactly how I wanted
to join the party.
Carrie: Everyone, stay on comms.
I'll do a sweep while you guys
figure out where
they put the bomb.
For maximum dispersal,
they'll have put it
in the HVAC system.
Boiler room's this way.
But there might be
some of those Mutants
between here and there.
Duela: Yah! Mutant: Uhh!
Duela: Hmm. [Pipe clatters]
We gotta get this
thing out of here.
Harper: Wait, wait.
See that?
It's a mercury tilt switch.
Used to use it in
old thermostats.
You move it, mercury
closes the circuit.
Uh, what does that mean?
Harper: It means the Mutants
are smarter than we thought.
You move this thing... boom.
Then we have to disable it here.
Mutant: All right, listen
up. Rings, watches.
Trinkets. All in the bag.
Make a donation,
everybody. Let's go.
Mutant 2: I'll take
that. Rebecca: Brody.
Brody: Uhh! Mutant
1: Come on, come on.
Woman on phone: There's a lot of red tape
and I don't have that kind of authority.
I don't care how much red
tape you've gotta cut through.
There's gonna be a
lot more red down here
if you don't!
Release him. On my order.
Huh. You hear that?
So, here's what you're gonna do.
Do I honestly have to
tell you what will happen
if you give in to their demands?
Um, we make it
out of this alive?
You will be sending a
message to every criminal
that not only do we
negotiate with terrorists,
but we give them
everything they want.
Hardly. We're trading
one Mutant Leader
for the rest of his gang.
This place is surrounded.
They're not getting outta here.
And I am sending a message
to the criminals, Harvey.
Don't mess with us.
Careful. Don't
want to get bomb
all over your Valentino.
It's a May Nickel.
And that is a mutating algorithm
that deletes itself
once complete.
Turner: Uh, what happens
when it deletes itself?
It deletes us.
[Tape ripping]
Don't want this
one getting loose
while I go handle his buddies.
Harper: Uh, guys? I just
searched for the frequency
that'll deactivate this thing
and there isn't one.
Just one to activate it.
So, it was meant to turn
on and never turn off.
So, the bomb's going
off no matter what?
That'd kill the
Mutants along with us.
Unless they planned ahead.
They all brought these.
Maybe they always
intended to gas the place.
Duela: Gotta say, it's kind
of the perfect escape plan.
The GCPD releases the Mutant
Leader, they set off the bomb.
The GCPD doesn't release the Mutant
Leader, they set off the bomb,
and then they all
peace out of here while
seizures and
suffocation get to fight
over what kills us first.
Great. Huh. Just
gonna hang on to this.
How much time do we
have to defuse it?
42 minutes. And that's if
the GCPD doesn't release
the Mutant Leader before then.
We have to warn them not to.
Buy ourselves as much
time as possible.
Yeah. We're the last
ones they'll believe.
There is one person the
GCPD will believe. Harvey.
I just gotta make
him believe me first.
OK, and if he doesn't,
he'll have you arrested.
You're gonna risk that?
A lot of people
will die if I don't.
Mutant: Sit down now. Quiet.
Nobody's gonna get hurt.
Mutant 2: Calm down.
We've already taken
what we wanted from you.
Have a seat.
Come with me.
Mutant: Sit down now. Quiet.
Ahh. OK. OK.
If you're gonna kill me,
just get it over with.
I'm not gonna kill you.
Turner.
What the hell are
you doing here?
We don't have much time.
That gas bomb is
in the boiler room,
and as soon as their leader
is released, the Mutant Gang
are gonna set it off.
That's their exit strategy.
Kill everybody here,
escape in the chaos.
You show up here
and you're dressed
like one of them
and now you're telling
me that you know
what they're
planning to do? How?
You need to trust me.
How can I do that?
You're a fugitive who ran.
Because I was framed.
Then why not let me help you?
Because you can't.
You asked me before if
I knew what that coin
they found on my dad meant.
I didn't know then.
But I do now.
It's the symbol of
the Court of Owls.
They're a secret cabal that's
been pulling strings in Gotham
since the city was founded.
Turner, this is insane.
Listen. The Court
killed my dad.
And now they're
trying to kill me.
And the others.
We can't trust anyone.
Then why trust me?
Because my dad did.
What do you need me to do?
Harper: We could try to cut
off the outflow of the aerosol.
Stop it from releasing the gas.
And if the stainless steel
can't contain the pressure,
then, congratulations,
you've just turned
a chemical bomb
into a regular bomb.
I suppose you have
a better idea?
Yeah. Not doing your idea.
Right, because Gotham
Academy is renowned
for its Honors Bomb
Defusing classes.
Nope, just basic science.
We're better off
disrupting the power source
to the valve that
pressurizes it.
That's your solution?
Cut the wire?
What's next? Bang
on it with a hammer?
The Mutants could've built
in a hidden redundancy,
in which case you
cut the primary,
this thing hot-boxes half
the city's power players.
Oh, uh, and us.
[Radio chirps] Carrie:
Can you read me?
Me and Duela took out as
many Mutants as we could.
All that's left are the
ones in the Gallery.
How are you two
doing down there?
Can I talk to you?
You have to recall the order
to release the Mutant Leader.
Why the hell would I do that?
Because if you don't,
we're all dead.
It's a double-cross.
They're gonna gas this place
the moment you set him free.
Who told you that?
I'm asking you to please
just trust me on this.
Trust the guy that wants my job?
Man: Prisoner coming through.
Delta on point.
Transfer team ready.
Let's move him out now.
[Cell phone chimes]
And things just got worse.
Cullen says they've
released the Mutant Leader.
Carrie, you guys need
to take out the rest of
those Mutants, like, now.
As you requested,
Vernon Wagner has been
released into the sewer system.
Well ahead of your deadline.
[Cell phone rings]
That's probably him now.
[Cell phone ringing]
Vernon on phone: I'm
in the subway system.
You are good to go.
Our leader's been released!
[Mutants cheering]
Now you will all be free.
Uhh!
[Both grunting]
Turner: Whatever
you're gonna do,
do it now.
Turner: We have to
shut that bomb down.
OK, I'm gonna disable
the pressure valve.
Too late.
Wait, no!
[Both grunt]
[Thud] [Crowd cheering]
Officer: Freeze! Police!
[Cheering and applause]
What the hell was that?
Excuse me?
You know what I'm talking about.
You mean the part where
I saved our lives?
No, the part where you
took a chance with my life.
Which you still
have, thanks to me.
You cut the wire without
knowing what would happen.
Because I knew what
would happen if I didn't.
You do realize the only
way you win this argument
is by being dead, right?
No, because my way
would have worked,
only you didn't give
me a chance because
I didn't go to some
fancy private school,
but that does not make
you smarter than me.
I never said that.
Yeah. You did when
you cut that wire.
This isn't your
daddy's game show.
Now, why don't you go
back to your cozy bedroom
on the top floor
of your mansion.
Easier to look down
on me from there.
Man on TV: While the hostage
situation has been resolved,
the leader of the Mutant
Gang is once again at large,
but Gotham can rest
a bit easier tonight,
thanks in part to the heroic
efforts... and fists...
Of District Attorney
Harvey Dent.
Mr. Dent, we didn't find any
explosive devices on the premises.
What? He had a detonator.
We swept the facility,
including the ventilator ducts.
Nothing. Maybe the
Mutants were bluffing
to get their leader out.
Damn it.
So, we save everyone's lives
and Harvey Dent
gets all the credit?
Look, he can have
the credit as long as
we can have the shiny stuff.
And what the Mutants take...
[Gasp]
we taketh away.
I know what you're gonna
say. "This is so wrong.
The gala guests
were victims, too."
Not all of them.
It's a Court of Owls watch.
Just like the one Ford had.
So is this one.
The Court of Owls
were at the gala
and we didn't even know it.
There were over
200 people there.
Which means we have no way
of knowing who they are.
Well, maybe this will
help us find them.
As promised. Every
scrap of paper
the GCPD has on
Alan Wayne's death.
Autopsy reports, eyewitness
statements, all of it.
If the Court did kill
him, hopefully there's
something in here
that'll lead us to them.
Uhh!
Think I'll do your
sparring partner a favor
and call a TKO.
They let him go.
After everything the
Mutant Leader has done,
and all the people he's hurt.
And they let him go.
I know. It's insane.
It's Gotham.
You try to change it
and it just changes you.
Makes me wonder
why I even do it.
Because you're
really good at it.
Not easy to say it,
but I gotta admit:
I'm jealous of you.
I see why my dad wanted
you as his Robin.
I just wish I'd gotten
to see that side of him.
Turner... you got to
see the side of him
that I never did.
The man who takes his
kid on camping trips.
Dad.
I was so young when my dad died.
I never got to experience
that kind of stuff.
So, I'm jealous of you.
Well, it's clear
from his journals
how much he cared about you.
It's also clear just
how responsible he felt
for every bad thing
that every bad guy
did in Gotham that
he didn't stop.
It was eating him up inside.
And I can't imagine
he'd want that for you.
My dad didn't want me
going down his path.
And I may never know why.
But I do know...
following in his footsteps
makes me feel closer to him.
He wouldn't want you to bear
the weight of his legacy alone.
Let me help you.
Risking your freedom to
save all those people?
It was very brave.
And, Turner,
your dad would be
so proud of you.
Is that a yes? Come on.
What did you say that
night you followed my dad?
What convinced him
to let you help him?
I didn't convince
him. Not that time.
He said no. And then
I followed him again
and then I asked him
again and he said no.
Actually, I got a lot of nos.
But I just kept on asking.
I guess I never gave up.
Kinda sucks to be the
Mutant Leader then.
With that kind of persistence...
he won't be free for long.
Was not easy, but I got it.
Not sure why you wanted
that from evidence lockup.
I thought you hated him.
Oh, I do.
This is just so I
don't forget how much.
Harper: Cullen?
No, I don't want to hear it.
You walked into a building
with a bomb in it.
You're the last person
who gets to lecture me
about doing something
dangerous. I can handle myself.
Harper: I know that.
Cullen: Really?
'Cause you've been treating me
like some weak, scared, little kid.
Harper: Cullen. Winona
Oak: ♪ This love from me ♪
♪ I don't... ♪
Harper: You've never
backed down from a fight.
Not against Dad,
not against anybody.
Cullen, you are the
bravest person I know.
Winona Oak: ♪ I'll
be fine, I promise ♪
I learned that from my
pain-in-the-ass sister, so.
Winona Oak: ♪ It's
all too late ♪
♪ So I'll stay till I break ♪
I've been a citizen of
Gotham my whole life.
I grew up in Cobble Hill, just
across the river. [Crowd cheering]
Ha ha! That's right.
For as long as I can remember,
unchecked crime and corruption
have cast a dark
shadow over this city.
And I think it's time we
remind those criminals
that we are not helpless.
We will no longer live
in the grip of fear.
That we will fight
for a better Gotham,
[Crowd cheering] fight
for a brighter tomorrow.
[Buzz] Get us the
hell out of here!
And we will let a new
dawn of hope shine down
on the streets of
this great city.
That is what I want.
No! No!
No! Oh, no! No!
[Gasping, coughing]
Harvey: And that
is why I am running
for mayor of Gotham.
Man: Greg, move your head.